const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Carbamoyl phosphate synthetase II (CPS-II) is allosterically inhibited by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Adenosine triphosphate (ATP)","bool":false},{"option":"Uridine monophosphate (UMP)","bool":false},{"option":"Uridine diphosphate (UDP)","bool":false},{"option":"Uridine triphosphate (UTP)","bool":true},{"option":"Phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate (PRPP)","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 32-year-old lady comes to the ultrasound department for an antenatal scan which shows bilateral hydronephrosis, hydro-ureters, and a distended urinary bladder with a keyhole sign in the fetus. The fetus is suspected with a case of posterior urethral valves. She is advised to have a post-natal checkup of the baby. What is the investigation of choice in this particular case?","answers":[{"option":"Kidney, ureter, and bladder (KUB) X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Voiding cystourethrogram (VCUG)","bool":true},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography scan (CT scan)","bool":false},{"option":"Repeat ultrasound KUB + Prostate","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 4-year-old girl presents with severe pitting edema. Further investigations show hypoalbuminemia, lipiduria, and 3.8 g proteinuria. Biopsy confirms the renal disease. Which of the following best describes the pathophysiology of proteinuria in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Tubulointerstitial damage","bool":false},{"option":"Crescent formation in the glomeruli","bool":false},{"option":"Derangement in glomerular capillary walls","bool":true},{"option":"Anti–glomerular basement membrane (anti-GBM) antibodies cross reacting with alveolar basement membranes","bool":false},{"option":"Excess dietary protein intake","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is formed as a result of deamination of cytosine?","answers":[{"option":"Methyl cytosine","bool":false},{"option":"Adenine","bool":false},{"option":"Uracil","bool":true},{"option":"Cytidylic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 5-year-old boy presents with generalized edema and periorbital edema. Further investigations show hypoalbuminemia, lipiduria, and 3.7 g proteinuria. Which of the following conditions is the most likely cause in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Amyloidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Amina has recently completed her FCPS and now she is pursuing her career as a specialist. She was passionate about this field and always wanted to serve society and live a meaningful life. Which of the following approach of happiness most likely focuses on meaning and self-realization?","answers":[{"option":"Hedonism","bool":false},{"option":"Eudemonia","bool":true},{"option":"Subjective well being","bool":false},{"option":"Psychological well-being","bool":false},{"option":"Happiness","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the alkaline nature of the extracellular fluid and acidic urine termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Glucosuria","bool":false},{"option":"Phenyl ketonuria","bool":false},{"option":"Ketonuria","bool":false},{"option":"Amino aciduria","bool":false},{"option":"Paradoxical aciduria","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"An adult male had a road traffic accident and went into a hypovolemic shock due to blood loss. Which intravenous fluid is preferable to start as initial available therapy in an emergency?","answers":[{"option":"Haemaccel","bool":true},{"option":"Ringer's lactate","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":false},{"option":"Amino acid solution","bool":false},{"option":"5% dextrose water","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"In a 60-year-old diabetic patient, a routine lab investigation shows hemoglobin: 8.2 gm/dL, creatinine (Cr): 5.0 mg/dL, calcium (Ca): 6.7 mg/dL, phosphate(PO4): 5.2 mg/dL, with small kidneys on ultrasound. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute kidney injury","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic kidney disease","bool":true},{"option":"Acute interstitial nephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"In a patient with severe dehydration, the plasma osmolality increases. This is corrected by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Angiotensin-II","bool":false},{"option":"Aldosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Antidiuretic hormone (ADH)","bool":true},{"option":"Increased intake of glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in protein intake","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which one of the following confirms the diagnosis of gout?","answers":[{"option":"Presence of urate crystals in the synovial fluid","bool":true},{"option":"Renal stones","bool":false},{"option":"Redness and pain in joints","bool":false},{"option":"Increased uric acid excretion in urine","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperuricemia","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"In purine metabolism, what does the deamination of guanine yield?","answers":[{"option":"Thiamine","bool":false},{"option":"Xanthine","bool":true},{"option":"Methyl guanine","bool":false},{"option":"Uracil","bool":false},{"option":"Cytidylic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Mr. Mughees did not score well in the exam. He has pessimistic explanatory styles and attributed his failure to generalized bad luck i.e. 'I always had bad luck in all life situations' (stable and global attribution), which lead to him being depressed. Which one of the following could preferably explain the causes of negative events contrary to this pessimistic explanatory style?","answers":[{"option":"Internal, stable","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"External, unstable, specific","bool":false},{"option":"External, global, stable","bool":false},{"option":"Internal, specific, unstable","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is carbamoyl phosphate a precursor of?","answers":[{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Urea","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoxanthine","bool":false},{"option":"Xanthine","bool":false},{"option":"Ionosine","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What does renal correction of acute hyperkalemia result in?","answers":[{"option":"Increased secretion of H+","bool":false},{"option":"Alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Increased secretion of HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"Increased secretion of Na+","bool":false},{"option":"Acidosis","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following do the afferent arterioles arise from?","answers":[{"option":"Peritubular capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Intralobar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Interlobar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate artery","bool":false},{"option":"Interlobular artery","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the end product of purine metabolism in humans?","answers":[{"option":"Xanthine","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoxanthine","bool":false},{"option":"Urea","bool":false},{"option":"Inositol","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the most sensitive indicator of glomerular function?","answers":[{"option":"Serum ammonia","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine clearance","bool":true},{"option":"Serum creatinine","bool":false},{"option":"Serum urea","bool":false},{"option":"Urea clearance","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"The substance is freely filtered at the glomerular capillaries but is not excreted into the urine because all the filtered substance is reabsorbed from the tubules back into the blood. This pattern occurs for which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Electrolytes","bool":false},{"option":"Bases","bool":false},{"option":"Inulin","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine","bool":false},{"option":"Amino acids and glucose","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"This substance is freely filtered at the glomerular capillaries and is not reabsorbed, but additional quantities of this substance are secreted from the peritubular capillary blood into the renal tubules. Which substance is this?","answers":[{"option":"Organic acids and bases","bool":false},{"option":"Electrolytes","bool":false},{"option":"Amino acids and glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine","bool":true},{"option":"Inulin","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"This substance is freely filtered by the glomerular capillaries but is neither reabsorbed nor secreted. Therefore, its excretion rate is equal to the rate at which it was filtered. Which substance is this?","answers":[{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Electrolytes","bool":false},{"option":"Inulin","bool":true},{"option":"Creatinine","bool":false},{"option":"Amino acids","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following gives rise to the trigone of the bladder?","answers":[{"option":"Paramesonephric duct","bool":false},{"option":"Splanchnic mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Mullerian duct","bool":false},{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Mesonephric duct","bool":true}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is the correct sequence of branching pattern of renal arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Segmental artery > lobar artery > intralobular artery > arcuate artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lobar artery > segmental artery > intralobular artery > arcuate artery","bool":false},{"option":"Segmental artery > interlobar artery > lobar artery > arcuate artery","bool":false},{"option":"Segmental artery > lobar artery > interlobar artery > arcuate artery","bool":true},{"option":"Lobar artery > segmental artery > interlobar artery > arcuate artery","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following cells release the enzyme renin?","answers":[{"option":"Juxtaglomerular cells","bool":true},{"option":"Interstitial kidney cells","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Brush border cells","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulus parietal cells","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following forms the outermost layer of the kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Perinephric fat","bool":false},{"option":"Renal fascia","bool":true},{"option":"Peritoneum","bool":false},{"option":"Only fat","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrous capsule","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"An increase in which of the following leads to a subsequent decrease in the glomerular filtration rate?","answers":[{"option":"Glomerular capillary hydrostatic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Bowman's capsule plasma oncotic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Peritubular capillary hydrostatic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerular capillary plasma oncotic pressure","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is involved in the counter-current multiplier mechanism of kidneys?","answers":[{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Vasa recta","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulus","bool":false},{"option":"Peritubular arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following structures is only found in the renal medulla?","answers":[{"option":"Bowman's capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Minor calyces","bool":false},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Thin limb of loop of Henle","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the most common causative organism for acute pyelonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":true},{"option":"Enterobacter","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeroginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What effect does exogenous erythropoietin have on a patient who has end-stage renal disease with anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased blood volume","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Induces hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Increased blood pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased erythrocyte production","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Erythropoietin is primarily formed in which organ?","answers":[{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow","bool":false},{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":true},{"option":"Liver","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"The hilum of the kidney is located in which plane?","answers":[{"option":"Median plane","bool":false},{"option":"Supine plane","bool":false},{"option":"Transpyloric plane","bool":true},{"option":"Transtubercular plane","bool":false},{"option":"Subcostal plane","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the arrangement of structures at the hilum of the kidney from anterior to posterior?","answers":[{"option":"Renal pelvis, vein, artery","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Vein, artery, renal pelvis","bool":true},{"option":"Artery, vein, renal pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Renal pelvis, artery, vein","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"The nephron is the functional unit of a kidney. Which of the following structures does urine pass through before entering the ureter?","answers":[{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Renal pelvis","bool":true},{"option":"Glomerulus","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 63-year-old female came to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, peristaltic pain, and hematuria. Her ultrasound reports revealed calculi in the conducting part of the urinary system. Where are the calculi most likely found?","answers":[{"option":"Minor calyx","bool":false},{"option":"Major calyx","bool":false},{"option":"Ureterovesical part of ureter","bool":true},{"option":"Pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Renal columns","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is the false statement regarding the posterior relations of the right kidney?","answers":[{"option":"12th rib","bool":false},{"option":"Quadratus lumborum","bool":false},{"option":"Psoas major","bool":false},{"option":"Iliohypogastric nerve","bool":false},{"option":"11th rib","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following structures lie in the center of the renal lobule?","answers":[{"option":"Interlobar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Cortical column","bool":false},{"option":"Medullary ray","bool":true},{"option":"Arcuate artery","bool":false},{"option":"Renal hilum","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 2nd-year medical student is looking at a histology slide of tissue with a narrow lumen lined by transitional epithelium. He can observe 3 layers of smooth muscles in its wall. Which structure is he observing?","answers":[{"option":"Vas deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Ureter","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following histological features is not specific to the proximal convoluted tubule?","answers":[{"option":"They have striated borders due to basal infoldings of plasma membrane","bool":false},{"option":"They are lined by simple cuboidal/low columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"They have microvilli on their luminal surfaces forming a brush border","bool":false},{"option":"They are more eosinophilic due to numerous mitochondria","bool":false},{"option":"They do not have a typical brush border as compared to the distal convoluted tubule","bool":true}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A double ureter anomaly results from the failure of normal development of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Metanephros","bool":false},{"option":"Pronephros","bool":false},{"option":"Mesonephros (Wolffian) duct","bool":false},{"option":"Ureteric bud","bool":true},{"option":"Paramesonephric duct","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the most abundant buffer in the proximal tubular fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Ammonia","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphate","bool":true},{"option":"Lactate","bool":false},{"option":"Protein","bool":false},{"option":"Bicarbonate","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the principle mechanism of H+ ion secretion into the proximal convoluted tubule?","answers":[{"option":"H-ATPase","bool":false},{"option":"Na-H symport","bool":false},{"option":"Na-H exchanger","bool":true},{"option":"H-Ca exchanger","bool":false},{"option":"H-HCO₃-ATPase","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"At what volume of urine, is the micturition reflex initiated?","answers":[{"option":"250 ml - 300 ml","bool":false},{"option":"150 ml -200 ml","bool":false},{"option":"300 ml - 400 ml","bool":true},{"option":"450 ml - 500 ml","bool":false},{"option":"100 ml - 150 ml","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the dietary effect of high protein intake and increased blood glucose on renal nephrons?","answers":[{"option":"Increase Bowman's capsule hydrostatic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Increase afferent arteriolar constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Increase efferent arteriolar constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Increase glomerular colloid oncotic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Increase sodium reabsorption in proximal convoluted tubules","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"The clearance of which endogenously produced substance is used to assess normal renal function?","answers":[{"option":"Urea","bool":false},{"option":"Para-amino hippuric acid (PAH)","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium ions","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine","bool":true},{"option":"Inulin","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What may the kidneys enhance in response to acidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Secretion of Na⁺ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of HCO₃⁻","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of K⁺ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Urea retention","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of H⁺ ions","bool":true}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What do the kidneys enhance in response to alkalosis?","answers":[{"option":"N₂-retention","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of H⁺ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of K⁺ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of HCO₃⁻","bool":true},{"option":"Secretion of Na⁺ ions","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following will decrease the amount of potassium excreted from the kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Circulating level of aldosterone increases","bool":false},{"option":"The excretion of organic ions increase","bool":false},{"option":"Na+ reabsorption by the distal nephron decreases","bool":true},{"option":"Dietary intake of potassium increases","bool":false},{"option":"Distal tubular flow increases","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"How can the body get rid of the huge acid load produced by metabolic reactions?","answers":[{"option":"Breathe faster and more deeply","bool":false},{"option":"Increase the concentration of protein ions in the plasma","bool":false},{"option":"Excrete hydrogen ions into the urine","bool":true},{"option":"Increase lipids in the blood","bool":false},{"option":"Increase the concentration of sodium ions","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 10-year-old boy develops severe diarrhea while traveling to South Asia. The laboratory investigation revealed the following: arterial blood pH = 7.25, partial pressure of carbon dioxide = 24 mmHg, bicarbonate = 10 mEq/L, normal anion gap. What is the correct diagnosis of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Hypercapnea","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which hormone regulates sodium and water content in the human body?","answers":[{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-diuretic hormone","bool":true},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Cortisone","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the normal plasma sodium concentration?","answers":[{"option":"135 to 145 mEq/L","bool":true},{"option":"85 to 105 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"35 to 75 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"155 to 175 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"115 to 125 mEq/L","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Where is the largest portion of water (28 liters) present?","answers":[{"option":"Intracellular compartment","bool":true},{"option":"Blood","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Extracellular compartment","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial compartment","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Ionization of water is the basis of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Solubility","bool":false},{"option":"pH scale","bool":true},{"option":"Viscosity","bool":false},{"option":"Diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Adsorption","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the predominant cation of plasma?","answers":[{"option":"Ca⁺²","bool":false},{"option":"Mg⁺²","bool":false},{"option":"Fe⁺²","bool":false},{"option":"Na⁺","bool":true},{"option":"K⁺","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the normal plasma potassium reference value?","answers":[{"option":"3.5 - 5.4 mEq/L","bool":true},{"option":"1 - 2.2 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"5.5 - 7.6 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"1.5 - 2.5 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"6.5 - 7.7 mEq/L","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 41-year-old has had recurrent urinary tract infections for 15 years. On many of these occasions, Proteus mirabilis was cultured from his urine. For the past 4 days, he has had burning pain while urinating, and urinary frequency. On examination, his temperature is 37.9°C, pulse is 70/min, and blood pressure is 135/85 mmHg. There is marked tenderness on deep pressure over the right costovertebral angle and on deep abdominal palpation. Urinalysis shows a pH of 7.5, specific gravity 1.020, 1+ hematuria, and no protein, glucose, or ketones. Microscopic examination of the urine shows many RBCs, WBCs, and triple phosphate crystals. Which of the following renal lesions is most likely to be present?","answers":[{"option":"Acute tubular necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Malignant nephrosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Papillary necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Renal cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Staghorn calculus","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Normal blood levels of urea and creatinine is critical for survival. What are the raised levels of urea and creatinine with clinical features known as?","answers":[{"option":"Uremic coma","bool":false},{"option":"Azotemia","bool":false},{"option":"Renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Uremia","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic pyelonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Immunologic mechanisms underlie most forms of glomerular disorders. Which of the following immunologic mechanisms of glomerular injuries is most common?","answers":[{"option":"Type-1 hypersensitivty reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Antibody-mediated injury","bool":true},{"option":"Activation of alternative complement pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Cell-mediated injury","bool":false},{"option":"Activation of intrinsic coagulation pathway","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 78-year-old man is admitted to a hospital due to acute urinary tract obstruction. For the past few years, he has had concurrent bouts of cystitis. Two days before being admitted to the hospital, he could not urinate at all. What is the most probable cause of bladder outlet obstruction in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Prostatic adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Nodular prostatic hyperplasia","bool":true},{"option":"Urethral stricture","bool":false},{"option":"Urothelial cell carcinoma of the bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrogenic metaplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 35-year-old man came to the outpatient department with complaints of repeated urinary tract infections. His urine D/R reports show pus cells = 12-15/High power field (HPF), red blood cells = 3-5/HPF, and triple phosphate crystals in the urine. Which of the following could be the cause of infection in such a case?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Serratia","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":true},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobacter","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 36-year-old married lady came to the outpatient department with a history of flank pain and difficulty in micturition. She also gave a history of weakness, fever in the evening, and a feeling of ill-health. She had not been feeling like eating recently. Her urine D/R showed 25-30 pus cells/High power field (HPF). Her erythrocyte sedimentation rate was 125 in the first hour. Her culture report was negative. What could've been the cause of her illness?","answers":[{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following research types is aimed at discovering the underlying subjective views or experiences, motives, and desires, finding reasons for human behavior (i.e., why people think or do certain things)?","answers":[{"option":"Quantitative research","bool":false},{"option":"Medical research","bool":false},{"option":"Hospital based research","bool":false},{"option":"Clinical research","bool":false},{"option":"Qualitative research","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 36-year-old is diagnosed with colorectal cancer. As the treating physician, it is your duty to educate him regarding the nature of his illness and its treatment. It is supposed to be conducted in a detailed and professional manner, using simple language which he will understand. What is this process called?","answers":[{"option":"Informational care","bool":true},{"option":"Crises intervention","bool":false},{"option":"Psychotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Research","bool":false},{"option":"Counselling","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 55-year-old female patient belonging to a rural area of Balochistan presented to you in the outpatient department and was diagnosed with diabetes. She is accompanied by her 14-year-old son who speaks and understands Urdu partially while the patient does not. You need to provide informational care to the patient but the language is an obstacle. Which of the following would be the appropriate course of action in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Admit the patient till you can find a doctor who speaks their language","bool":false},{"option":"Prescribe medication and do not provide informational care","bool":false},{"option":"Provide informational care to her son","bool":false},{"option":"Ask a colleague who speaks their language to provide informational care to the patient","bool":true},{"option":"Refer her to a doctor in Balochistan","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the most important investigation for differentiating between renal and pre-renal acute renal failure?","answers":[{"option":"Computed tomography (CT) pyelogram","bool":false},{"option":"Serum creatinine","bool":false},{"option":"Urine detailed report","bool":true},{"option":"Arterial blood gases","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound kidneys, ureters, and bladder (KUB)","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the most common cause of acute renal injury?","answers":[{"option":"Acute tubular necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Acute glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Pre-renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Post-renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Tubulo-interstitial nephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"You visit a patient in the intensive care unit. The patient is a thin elderly female with a history of femur fracture and has been bed-bound for the past 1 year. While going through her lab values, you notice a sodium concentration of 125 mmol/L. The patient is asymptomatic for the signs of hyponatremia and is euvolemic. What first step will you take after looking at the sodium?","answers":[{"option":"Repeat sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Add sodium chloride tablet","bool":false},{"option":"Free water restriction","bool":true},{"option":"Start hypertonic saline immediately","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the composition of sodium and chloride in 0.9% normal saline?","answers":[{"option":"Na 159, Cl 154","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Na 154, Cl 154","bool":true},{"option":"Na 154, Cl 150","bool":false},{"option":"Na 150, Cl 154","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 10-year-old male presents with palpable purpura in the lower extremities and buttocks area. Investigations reveal a decreased glomerular filtration rate (GFR) with a nephritic picture. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Henoch-Schönlein purpura","bool":true},{"option":"Post streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the primary indication for micturating cystourethrography?","answers":[{"option":"Acute urinary tract infection","bool":false},{"option":"Vesicoureteric reflux","bool":true},{"option":"Fistula","bool":false},{"option":"Urethral trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Urethral malignancy","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is the gold standard for diagnosing Helicobacter pylori?","answers":[{"option":"Histopathology","bool":false},{"option":"Urease test","bool":false},{"option":"Urea breath test","bool":false},{"option":"Microbiological culture","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Allopurinol is a structural analog of which of the following compounds?","answers":[{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Xanthine oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Inosine monophosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphoribosyl pyrophosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxanthine","bool":true}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the osmolarity of the glomerular filtrate that enters the proximal convoluted tubule?","answers":[{"option":"300 mOsm/L","bool":true},{"option":"100 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"1200 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"400 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"200 mOsm/L","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"In which lymph nodes does the abdominal part of the ureter drain?","answers":[{"option":"Deep inguinal nodes","bool":false},{"option":"External iliac nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Common iliac nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Paraaortic nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Internal iliac nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 25-year-old male presented to the outpatient department with symptoms of nephrotic syndrome. The biopsy showed normal histology with effacement of foot processes on electron microscopy. Which disease is he likely to have?","answers":[{"option":"Acute pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following arteries supplies the upper part of the ureter?","answers":[{"option":"Internal iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"External iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"Common iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"Gonadal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Renal artery","bool":true}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following increase in metabolic alkalosis?","answers":[{"option":"HCO3 only","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma pH and HCO3","bool":true},{"option":"Plasma pH only","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma pH and pCO2","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma pH and lactic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Change occurs in which part of the bladder when it is filled with urine?","answers":[{"option":"Fundus","bool":false},{"option":"Trigone","bool":false},{"option":"Body","bool":true},{"option":"Neck","bool":false},{"option":"Base","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the osmolarity of the interstitial fluid in the renal medulla?","answers":[{"option":"1800 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"600 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"1200 mOsm/L","bool":true},{"option":"1000 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"800 mOsm/L","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Increased secretion of aldosterone leads to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hyponatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypernatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"The kidneys lie at which vertebral level?","answers":[{"option":"T12-L1","bool":false},{"option":"T12-L4","bool":false},{"option":"T12-L2","bool":false},{"option":"T11-L3","bool":false},{"option":"T12-L3","bool":true}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"The renal medulla contains 6-8 pyramids. What is the extension of the cortex between these pyramids called?","answers":[{"option":"Minor calyx","bool":false},{"option":"Cortical columns","bool":true},{"option":"Major calyx","bool":false},{"option":"Medullary rays","bool":false},{"option":"Cortical rays","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 65-year-old male presented with a complaint of dysuria. His complete urinalysis showed gram-negative rods that were non-lactose fermenting and had swarming movements. What is the most probable cause?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus vulgaris","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":true},{"option":"Enterococcus faecalis","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Where are specialized cells with primary and secondary processes found?","answers":[{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Macula densa","bool":false},{"option":"Bowman's capsule","bool":true},{"option":"Collecting duct","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which urea transporter is present in the loop of Henle for urea secretion?","answers":[{"option":"UT-1","bool":false},{"option":"UT-5","bool":false},{"option":"UT-2","bool":true},{"option":"UT-3","bool":false},{"option":"UT-4","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following hormones acts on the principal cells of the nephrons?","answers":[{"option":"Parathyroid hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Aldosterone","bool":true},{"option":"Anti-diuretic hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Angiotensin","bool":false},{"option":"Cortisol","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is not true about sodium reabsorption in the proximal convoluted tubule?","answers":[{"option":"65% of filtered load is reabsorbed","bool":false},{"option":"80% of filtered load is reabsorbed","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Reabsorption occurs through Na⁺-H⁺ ATPase pump","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium shares the same transporter as glucose","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which substances are required for the de novo synthesis of pyrimidines?","answers":[{"option":"Glutamine and aspartate","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamine, carbon dioxide, and aspartate","bool":true},{"option":"Aspartate only","bool":false},{"option":"NADH only","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamine and NADH","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Increased HCO₃⁻ excretion replaces Cl⁻ in the urine due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Increased Na⁺-H⁺ exchange","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased Na⁺-H⁺ exchange","bool":false},{"option":"Retention of acid metabolites","bool":true},{"option":"Ketoacidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Increased acid secretion","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"In which part of the nephron is the Na⁺-K⁺-2Cl⁻ transporter most abundant?","answers":[{"option":"Collecting duct","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Thin ascending limb of loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Thin descending limb of loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Thick ascending limb of loop of Henle","bool":true}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is the mechanism by which calcium ions are reabsorbed in the proximal convoluted tubule?","answers":[{"option":"Transcellular route","bool":false},{"option":"Paracellular route","bool":true},{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary active transport","bool":false},{"option":"Active transport","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A female comes into the clinic with oral ulcers, hematuria, and +1 proteinuria. 1-2 white blood cells/HPF are found on urinalysis. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Lupus nephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Acid excretion","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A young man presents to the outpatient department with urethral discharge. Urinalysis shows neutrophils but there are no bacteria found. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":false},{"option":"Candida albicans","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":true},{"option":"Coxiella burnetii","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What should be the target blood pressure of a person having chronic kidney failure with 1+ proteinuria?","answers":[{"option":"140/90 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"160/100 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"150/90 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"130/80 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"125/75 mmHg","bool":true}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A patient complains of dysuria, fever, urinary frequency, and hematuria. His urinalysis shows numerous white blood cells, nitrite positive, and few red blood cells. What is true about the most common causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Catalase negative gram-positive rods","bool":false},{"option":"Gram-negative spiral rods","bool":false},{"option":"Urease positive gram-negative rods","bool":false},{"option":"Catalase positive gram-positive rods","bool":false},{"option":"Indole positive gram-negative rods","bool":true}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is an extrinsic cause of unilateral partial obstruction of the ureter?","answers":[{"option":"Congenital vesicoureteral reflux","bool":false},{"option":"Retroperitoneal fibrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Renal calculi","bool":false},{"option":"Ectopic fused kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Horseshoe kidney","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A man came with the complaint of right lumbar pain and hematuria for four hours. Which of the following should be the choice of investigation?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasound KUB","bool":true},{"option":"Plain radiography KUB","bool":false},{"option":"MRI scan","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray KUB","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 2.2x2.4 cm mass is accidentally found on ultrasound at the lower pole of the kidney. What should be the subsequent investigation of choice?","answers":[{"option":"CT scan","bool":true},{"option":"Plain radiography KUB","bool":false},{"option":"MRI pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound KUB","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray KUB","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following structures holds the kidney in its position?","answers":[{"option":"Perinephric fat","bool":false},{"option":"Renal fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen bundles","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":true},{"option":"Paranephric fat","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following urine culture results gives the diagnosis of urinary tract infection?","answers":[{"option":"100-1000 CFU/ml","bool":false},{"option":"50000-100000 CFU/ml","bool":false},{"option":"100000-200000 CFU/ml","bool":true},{"option":"1000-5000 CFU/ml","bool":false},{"option":"10000-100000 CFU/ml","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"At the end of an information care session, the patient briefly summarises which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Details of the doctor","bool":false},{"option":"Details of the drug","bool":false},{"option":"Details of the disease","bool":false},{"option":"Details of the disease, drug, and doctor","bool":true}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following are delicate matrix-forming cells present among the glomerular capillaries, having contractile nature, and are phagocytic?","answers":[{"option":"Podocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule cells","bool":false},{"option":"Mesangial cells","bool":true},{"option":"Juxtaglomerular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Basal lamina cells","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is a congenital abnormality that occurs due to the persistence of urachus resulting in an opening between the umbilicus and the urinary bladder?","answers":[{"option":"Urachal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Urachal fistula","bool":true},{"option":"Urachal cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is the remnant of the urachus?","answers":[{"option":"Umbilicus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial umbilical ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral umbilical ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Umbilical artery","bool":false},{"option":"Median umbilical ligament","bool":true}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A two-year-old boy presented with recurrent urinary tract infections. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Dysplastic kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital vesicoureteral reflux","bool":true},{"option":"Horseshoe kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic kidney disease","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is the narrowest part of the ureter, well above the urinary bladder, where stones can get lodged?","answers":[{"option":"Pelvicalyceal junction","bool":false},{"option":"Major calyx","bool":false},{"option":"Minor calyx","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic brim","bool":true},{"option":"Bladder wall","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A female patient was on antibiotic therapy for urinary tract infections. She later developed a fever and rash.  Her urine had increased eosinophils. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Renal papillary necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute tubular necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Nephritic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Acute interstitial nephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Drug induced interstitial nephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"One-third of total body water is found in which of the following compartments?","answers":[{"option":"Interstitial","bool":false},{"option":"Intracellular","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma","bool":false},{"option":"Intracellular and interstitial","bool":false},{"option":"Extracellular","bool":true}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is measured using para-amino hippuric acid?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Renal plasma flow","bool":true},{"option":"Glomerular filtration rate","bool":false},{"option":"Urine output","bool":false},{"option":"Renal blood flow","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is incorrect about the development of the urogenital system?","answers":[{"option":"Urethral folds merge on the ventral aspect of the penile urethra","bool":false},{"option":"All statements are correct","bool":false},{"option":"Prostatic urethra is derived from the pelvic part of the urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous urethra is derived from the phallic part of the urogenital sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Hypospadias is the failure of the closure of the urethral folds","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following statements is correct about the urogenital system?","answers":[{"option":"Podocytes are derived from the endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Macula densa secrete renin","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney become functional at the end of 2nd trimester","bool":false},{"option":"Distal tubules show brush border","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting ducts are derived from the mesoderm","bool":true}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 65-year-old man came with a complaint of recurrent flank pain. Ultrasound revealed hydronephrosis with distension of the pelvis and calyces but the bladder and ureters were normal. What is the most likely cause of his complaint?","answers":[{"option":"Ectopic fused kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Retroperitoneal fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital vesicoureteral reflux","bool":false},{"option":"Prostatic hyperplasia","bool":true},{"option":"Horseshoe kidney","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 65-year-old male came with complaints of fever, hematuria, and flank pain. He had white blood cell casts in his urine and his culture showed 10⁴ CFU/ml. What direction of investigation should be followed?","answers":[{"option":"10⁴ CFU/ml is not significant","bool":false},{"option":"Go for a pyelogram","bool":false},{"option":"Urine culture should be done again","bool":false},{"option":"Treat as a case of urinary tract infection","bool":true},{"option":"An ultrasound should be performed","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Dialysis is done in end stage renal disease as a replacement for renal function. Which of the following is correct regarding it?","answers":[{"option":"Preservation of arm veins is not important","bool":false},{"option":"Long term dialysis is done by two way catheter in the central vein","bool":false},{"option":"Long term catheter is placed in the femoral vein","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Formation of arteriovenous fistula","bool":true}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"What is true about hemodialysis of patient with end stage renal disease?","answers":[{"option":"Can be done at home 4 times per day","bool":false},{"option":"No need for hemodialysis in acute kidney injury","bool":false},{"option":"No restriction on diet and fluid intake","bool":false},{"option":"4 hour session thrice a week","bool":true},{"option":"Screening for hepatitis C is not required","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following structures is lined by transitional epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Nephron","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary bladder","bool":true},{"option":"Prostate gland","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting duct","bool":false},{"option":"Urethra","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which substance donates a single carbon atom in the pyrimidine ring?","answers":[{"option":"Carbon dioxide","bool":true},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Tetrahydrofolate","bool":false},{"option":"Aspartate","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is involved in the de novo synthesis of both purines and pyrimidines?","answers":[{"option":"Tetrahydrofolate","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamine, carbon dioxide, and aspartate","bool":true},{"option":"Aspartate","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Bilateral agenesis of the kidneys is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Polyhydramnios","bool":false},{"option":"Renal failure later in life","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Oligohydramnios","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertrophy of kidneys","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following causes an increase in the glomerular filtration rate?","answers":[{"option":"Sympathetic nervous system stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary tract obstruction","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelial derived nitric oxide","bool":true},{"option":"Angiotensin II","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is synthesized by the kidney and acts on the intestine?","answers":[{"option":"Erythropoietin","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":false},{"option":"Calcitriol","bool":true},{"option":"Parathyroid hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Calcitonin","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following are interrelated processes of the nephron?","answers":[{"option":"Filtration, reabsorption, and secretion","bool":true},{"option":"Filtration, secretion, and excretion","bool":false},{"option":"Filtration and excretion","bool":false},{"option":"Filtration, reabsorption, and excretion","bool":false},{"option":"Reabsorption, secretion, and excretion","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which is true regrading juxtaglomerular apparatus?","answers":[{"option":"Macula densa is a part of the proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Juxtaglomerular cells secrete renin","bool":true},{"option":"Juxtaglomerular cells are found in both afferent and efferent arterioles","bool":false},{"option":"Macula densa cells secrete renin","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Which of the following is not a congenital disease?","answers":[{"option":"Horseshoe kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Renal agenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Renal stones","bool":true},{"option":"Medullary cystic kidney disease","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"Sodium ions are reabsorbed in exchange of which of the following ions in the proximal convoluted tubule?","answers":[{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium ions","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride ions","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen ions","bool":true},{"option":"Phosphate ions","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A patient on dialysis could not find a kidney donor in the family. He is about to receive a kidney transplant from someone who is about to die. What will the donor be called?","answers":[{"option":"Genetically related donor","bool":false},{"option":"Non-related donor","bool":false},{"option":"Cadaveric donor","bool":true},{"option":"Living donor","bool":false},{"option":"Living unrelated donor","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2021","question":"A 4-year-old boy showed signs of diffuse effacement of foot processes on electron microscopy. What is correct about the disease?","answers":[{"option":"Dramatic response to corticosteroids","bool":true},{"option":"Progression to chronic renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Spike and dome appearance","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of immune complex deposits","bool":false}]}]
export default arr